New York. New rules.
Scream VI is a horror, crime, thriller film directed by Matt Bettinelli-Olpin.
Following the latest Ghostface killings, the four survivors
leave Woodsboro behind and start a fresh chapter.
Sam Carpenter, played by Melissa Barrera.
Tara Carpenter, played by Jenna Ortega.
Mindy Meeks-Martin, played by Jasmin Savoy Brown.
Chad Meeks-Martin, played by Mason Gooding.
Ethan Landry, played by Jack Champion.
'The Voice' (voice), played by Roger L. Jackson.
Scream VI is a 2023 American slasher film directed by Matt Bettinelli-Olpin and
Tyler Gillett, and written by James Vanderbilt and Guy Busick.
It is a sequel to Scream (2022) and the sixth
installment in the Scream film series.
The film stars Melissa Barrera, Jasmin Savoy Brown, Mason Gooding, Roger L.
Jackson, Jenna Ortega, Skeet Ulrich, Hayden Panettiere, and Courteney Cox, all reprising their roles from previous installments, with Jack Champion,
Henry Czerny, Liana Liberato, Dermot Mulroney, Devyn Nekoda, Tony Revolori, Josh Segarra, and Samara Weaving joining the ensemble cast.
The plot follows a new Ghostface killer, who begins targeting the
survivors of the Woodsboro murders in New York City.
A sixth Scream film was announced just weeks after
the successful debut of Scream (2022).
Much of the cast signed on to reprise their roles, with
Bettinelli-Olpin, Gillett, Vanderbilt, and Busick also returning.
Filming took place in Montreal, Canada, from June to late August 2022.
Neve Campbell did not reprise her role as Sidney Prescott due to a pay
dispute, making this the only Scream film not to feature her.
Brian Tyler, who had scored the fifth film, returned to compose and conduct
the score, with Sven Faulconer joining Tyler as a co-composer.
Scream VI premiered at the AMC Lincoln Square Theater in Manhattan on March 6, 2023, and was
theatrically released in the United States on March 10 by Paramount Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised the fresh setting
for the franchise, the increased violence, and the performances of the cast.
It grossed $169 million worldwide, becoming the first installment in the franchise to earn over $100 million at the domestic US box
office since Scream 2 (1997) and the highest-grossing Scream film in the United States and Canada (unadjusted for inflation).
It won Best Movie at the 2023 MTV Movie & TV Awards and ranked #3 on The
Hollywood Reporter's list of "The Best Slasher Movies of the Decade".
A sequel, Scream 7, is scheduled to be released on February 27, 2026.
The film explores themes of mask, new york city, trauma, halloween, college.
The tone is dark and intense.